They said it couldn't be done...
传说这是不可能发生的
the one called "Arcee" is too quick,
阿尔茜身手敏捷 神出鬼没
too stealthy to be captured.
根本无法擒获
Well, here you are,
不过 现在你却来到了此地
with a rare opportunity to make history.
还得到了创造历史的机会
You see, I have intercepted this encrypted Autobot signal,
你知道 我截获了一段汽车人的加密信息
and if it's encrypted,
既然是加密信息
it must be important.
就一定有重要内容
Decode it for me, and I will see to it that you perish quickly.
替我解开密文 我就给你个痛快的死法
Speak up. I can't hear you when you whimper.
大声点！哭哭啼啼地我听不见你在说些什么
Get... fragged.
去死吧
Perhaps you will be more inclined to cooperate
或许要让你屈服
when it is not your own well-being at stake.
得找另外的人来受罪
Arcee. Been a while.
阿尔茜 好久不见
Give me the encryption code,
告诉我加密代码
or I will add your comrade Cliffjumper to the multitude of fallen Autobots below.
否则你的同伴飞过山 就要下去跟汽车人尸骨堆做伴了
Scrap him. I barely know the guy.
让他死好了 我跟他不熟
Ouch. Glad I'm not the sensitive type.
噢 你伤害了我敏感的心
Cybertron is little more than a graveyard now.
如今的塞博特恩 已经和一个大坟场毫无二致
Give me the code!
告诉我密码！
I'm not afraid of you, Starscream.
我不怕你 红蜘蛛
You're no Megatron.
你不是威震天
Three steps, Bulkhead?
才三步 隔板？
That's all you can manage?
你就只能走这么远？
I'm sorry, Miko. My legs still hurt.
对不起神子 我的腿还疼着呢
What did I tell you?
我怎么跟你说的？
"No excuses."
没有借口
Exactly. Try again.
没错 再来一次
10 steps this time.
这次要迈十步
I hope decoding the Iacon database
我希望铁堡数据库解码的进展
is going more smoothly than Bulkhead's recovery.
能比隔板康复得更顺利一些
Slow but steady, old friend.
缓慢 但是稳定 我的老朋友
Agh. Human technology.
啊 人类科技！
But your expertise in the field should provide any edge
不过你在这一领域的专长
we need to beat the Decepticons at this game.
应该能让我们在这场竞赛中领先于霸天虎
I fear their access to Cybertronian technology
恐怕他们凭借塞博特恩的科技也不会落后到哪儿去
Not good enough!
还不够好！
You have to come back stronger than before!
你得要比以前更强壮
Time for a break, Bulkhead.
你得休息一会儿了 隔板
A break?
休息？
You think the 'Cons are gonna give Bulkhead a break in the middle of a fire fight?!
你觉得在交火中 虎子们会让隔板休息吗？
If you push a patient too far too fast,
你要是把病人逼得太紧
you risk exacerbating their injuries.
有可能加重伤情
But...
可是…
Bulkhead needs to rest.
隔板该休息了
Out of the way!
让开！
Miko?
神子
Oh. Uh... hey, Arcee. I was just...
哦呃 嘿 阿尔茜 我只是在…
Are we a little close to the edge?
是不是离悬崖太近了？
Heights don't scare me.
我不怕高
Bulkhead's coming along just fine.
隔板恢复得不错
Thanks mostly to your efforts.
这大部分都是你的功劳
But he needs a friend right now,
但是他现在需要的是朋友
not a drill sergeant.
而不是操练官
No offense, but I came up here for some privacy.
不好意思 我上来是想找点私人空间
I understand what you're going through.
我明白你的感受
If you ever want someone to talk to...
你要是想找人聊聊…
I'm fine, okay?
我很好 行了吧？
I'm not the one Hardshell tried to scrap.
硬壳差点杀死的不是我
Miko, it's rough when someone you care about gets hurt.
神子 你在乎的人受了伤 这的确令人难过
Closing yourself off from feeling... won't help anyone.
但封闭自己的感情 无济于事
Well, you would know, wouldn't you?
好吧 就像你明白似的？
Yes...
是的
I would.
我明白
Arcee, I'm sorry.
阿尔茜 很抱歉
I didn't mean that.
我不是故意提起的
It's okay. He's... been on my mind lately.
没关系 最近我正好在想他
After I lost my first partner, Tailgate,
我 失去挡板之后
I pushed everyone away.
远离了所有人
Until Cliffjumper came along.
直到飞过山出现了
What was he like?
他是什么样的人？
Cliff was... quite the conversationalist.
小飞他… 很健谈
Cliffjumper, are you...?
飞过山 你怎…
I... I can't... I can't believe you actually care.
我… 我没想到你真的关心我
The only thing I care about is whether you talked just now.
我只关心你还能不能讲话 你讲了
Are you always this nice to your rescuers?
你对来救你的人都是这种态度吗？
Didn't answer my question.
你没回答我的问题
I got bored with Starscream's little workout.
我厌倦了红蜘蛛小儿科般的拷问
So I idled my engines and faked shutdown.
于是我关闭了引擎 假装昏了过去
Scream bought it.
小红信了
How did you wind up here?
你怎么被抓来的？
Intercepted some chatter about a Decepticon operation on the old home planet.
我截获了霸天虎的通讯 听说他们在母星上有所行动
So I followed the trail and found Starscream
我一路跟踪 发现红蜘蛛
shipping massive amounts of Energon here to Cybertron.
从这里将大批能量运往塞博特恩
What's your story?
你呢？
Same.
一样
You're quite the conversationalist.
你还真健谈
I've tried every interrogation technique, and nothing is working.
各种审讯方式我都试过了 都不管用
I would just eliminate them, but the code they carry is too valuable.
要不是因为他们带着重要的密码 我早就杀了他们
If only I could break them open and just take it!
要是我能直接打开他们拿到密码就好了
No, I will not take the prisoners to the surface!
不 我不会把犯人送到地面上的！
Why should I let him have all the glory?
为什么要让他抢我的功劳？
The code they carry is too valuable.
他们带着重要的密码
All right, since I must deliver the Energon to him anyway...
好吧 反正我也得把能量送给他
So, this is Kaon, huh?
这里就是卡隆？
Love what you Decepticons have done with the place.
我真喜欢你们经营的这个地方
The ruins are especially picturesque.
这些废墟真是生机勃勃
Silence!
安静！
Here we are.
我们到了…
That's not a good sign.
这… 不是个好兆头
Since I could not compel you to surrender the encryption code,
既然我没法强迫你们说出加密代码
I'm forced to introduce you to someone whose methods are a little more...
我只好把你们交给手段更加…
persuasive.
有说服力的人
We may be in a little more trouble than I thought.
我们可能比我预想的还要惨
Autobots, say hello to Shockwave.
汽车人 来跟震荡波打个招呼吧
Delivering a mountain of Energon,
送出高如小山的能量
intercepting an encrypted Autobot communicate?
截取了汽车人的加密电报
and capturing two key prisoners is impressive, I admit.
还捕获了两个关键的俘虏 我承认这是很大的功劳
But lord Megatron expects nothing less from his first lieu...
不过威震天陛下对他副手的要求比这…
I should let you work, right?
…我是不是该让你开始工作了？
No doubt you are trying to concentrate. Carry on.
看来你需要专注 继续吧…
without first nullifying our subject's neural net?
而不是毁掉这个人的神经系统吗？
I invented the cortical psychic patch.
大脑神经接入器是我发明的
I am familiar with its idiosyncrasies.
我很清楚它的特性
Of course you are.
这是当然
Keep that thing away from me, you one-eyed freak!
别拿着那东西靠近我 你这个独眼怪物！
Leave her alone! Use it on me!
放开她 冲我来！
Do not worry.
别担心
If her mind does not survive the procedure,
要是她的神经承受不了这个过程
you will be next.
下一个就是你
Ah. The code.
啊 密码…
Arcee. Arcee! I'll scrap you both!
阿尔茜 阿尔茜！我要杀了你们两个！
Shut up! I'm trying to listen!
闭嘴！我在听！
This is Optimus Prime.
我是擎天柱
To all surviving Autobots who hear this message,
至所有收到这条信息的汽车人
I ask you to join me in a remote corner of the galaxy.
我邀请你们到银河系一个偏远的角落来与我会合
on a small planet rich with Energon.
这是一个充满能量的小星球
I have reason to believe this world will soon
我有理由推断
become a new target of Decepticon conquest.
这里很快就会成为霸天虎新的侵略目标
Our team is small but strong.
我的队伍小而精悍
Join me at these coordinates so that we might plan our resistance.
到这些坐标来与我会合 以便策划抵抗运动
Safe journeys.
一路平安
Aha! Brilliant!
啊 干得漂亮！
Not only do we know where to find Optimus Prime,
现在我们不但知道擎天柱的位置
but he's begging for help.
还知道他在求援
Now is the time to strike!
这正是突击的好时机！
You are no longer of use.
你没有利用价值了…
Hey, Scream. Curious...
嘿 小红 我很好奇
you always let other Cons do your dirty work?
你总是让别的虎子帮你下手吗？
Shockwave! You already disposed of one of my prisoners.
震荡波！你已经杀掉了一个我的俘虏
Cliffjumper is mine.
飞过山是我的
Your reasoning is hardly... logical.
你的想法很不合逻辑
But indulge yourself.
不过请自便
What do you think, Cliffjumper?
你觉得怎样 飞过山？
Plenty to choose from here.
这里的选择多种多样
Shall we go with precise dissection
我们是要精确的对半开呢？
or blunt force?
还是钝器呢？
Your choice, Scream. Whatever you pick,
随你选 小红 不管你选什么
I'm just gonna end up using it on you.
最终都是我用在你身上
Very well.
好吧
Why don't we do this the old-fashioned way?
要不我们来用最传统的方法
No! No!!
不 不！
Thanks for the save.
多谢相救
Your turn, Starscream.
该你说了 红蜘蛛
What's with all the Energon?
能量是用来做什么的？
As if I would tell you!
我怎么会告诉你
Talk, or you're a science experiment. I'm not kidding!
你不说 就用你做实验 我没有开玩笑！
You should probably tell her something.
你最好告诉她点东西
I'm not sure how long I can hold her back.
我不确定我能拖住她多久
I'm no expert with this thing,
这方面我不是专家
but I hear one slip-up can fry a neural net.
不过我知道 只要手一滑 就能烧毁整个神经系统
Shockwave! He's the one you want!
震荡波！你们该找的是他！
He's building a Space Bridge beneath Kaon.
他正在卡隆地下建造一个太空桥！
Impossible.
不可能
Space bridge technology's been lost for mega-cycles.
太空桥技术已经失传好几个兆周了！
And yet he managed!
但是他做到了！
Shockwave never left Cybertron precisely so he could scavenge parts
震荡波从不离开塞博特恩 正是因为他能回收到零件
and reverse-engineer space bridge mechanics!
并且通过反向工程研究出太空桥的原理！
And you just delivered all the Energon he needs to power it up.
你送来的能量刚好够他启动太空桥的！
While it often pains me, I try to be a team player.
是的 虽然这么做令我煎熬 不过我还是尝试着合作 呃！
Going somewhere?
你去哪儿？
To take down a space bridge.
去摧毁太空桥
Without me?
不带上我吗？
This'll require stealth/
这个行动需要隐蔽
Not... chatter.
而不是…闲扯
Oh, you mean the chatter that distracted Starscream long enough for you to free yourself?
你说的闲扯分散了红蜘蛛的注意力 好让你有时间挣脱
Just try not to slow me down.
别拖我后腿就成！
You know where you're going?
你知道怎么走吗？
My unit used these tunnels during the war.
我所在的部队曾经利用这些坑道活动
They're part of old Cybertron.
这是旧塞博特恩的一部分
The sooner we blow the bridge,
我们早点毁掉太空桥
the sooner we join up with Optimus Prime.
就能早点与擎天柱会合
Give him my regards.
代我向他问好
Did you not hear Prime's message?
你没听到擎天柱的信息吗？
He needs us.
他需要我们！
Teamwork isn't my thing.
我不擅长团队合作
after we finish this,
我们了结这件事之后
you and I go our separate ways.
你我各奔东西
Whatever you say, partner.
你说了算 搭档
Let's get one thing straight...
把话说清楚
you are not my partner.
你不是我的搭档！
Arcee, I know it's rough. I really do.
阿尔茜 我明白这不好受 真的
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
Tailgate.
挡板
Tailgate!
挡板！
Closing yourself off from feeling...
封闭自己的感情
- won't help anyone.
- 无济于事
Sounds familiar.
听着耳熟
Good advice is good advice.
那是个好建议
So, I got to know... what happened next?
我想知道 接下来怎样了？
Shockwave's latest work of art.
震荡波的最新杰作
Already fueled and ready to rip.
我已经感觉它要吸进去东西了
Arcee... look familiar?
阿尔茜 看那个眼熟吗？
The coordines Optimus provided.
擎天柱提供的坐标
They're being used to target the space bridge.
太空桥的目的地已经指向了那里
Which means the 'Cons will ambush Optimus
这意味着虎子们将会偷袭擎天柱的队伍
and his team. before any Autobot reinforcements can get there.
赶在汽车人的援军到达之前
If the 'Cons scorch Optimus,
要是虎子们杀害了擎天柱
the war is as good as over.
战争必败无疑
We can fix that.
我们能挽救这一切
No. We don't have the ordnance to blow the bridge.
不行 我们的能力不足以摧毁太空桥
I'll have to sabotage the control systems.
我得想办法破坏控制系统
What about access?
怎么做？
You just gonna walk up and ask for permission?
你打算走上去向他们寻求许可吗？
No... you are.
不 是你去
Uh, excuse me.
啊 不好意思
I got separated from the tour group.
我从观光团掉队了
Does anyone know where I can find the Decepticon base?
你们知道怎么去霸天虎基地吗？
Whoa! Didn't Commander Starscream tell you?
喔 红蜘蛛指挥官没有跟你们说过吗？
I'm on your side now.
我现在是你们一边的了
That coward Optimus Prime turned tail and ran.
那个胆小鬼擎天柱夹着尾巴溜了
Left the rest of us Autobots to fend for ourselves.
留下我们这些汽车人自求多福
So much for comraderie, huh?
毫无同伴情谊 哼
Figured I'd rather be on the winning team.
我想我还是加入胜利者的队伍好了
So I took Starscream up on his offer.
于是接受了红蜘蛛的招安
Imagine the look on Prime's face when it starts raining Decepticons...
猜猜看擎天柱看到 满天霸天虎降落时是什么表情！
me with them.
我也在其中！
Really, I know all about Starscream's plan.
看 我知道红蜘蛛的所有计划
We can all get along now.
我们会相处得很好的
There's... someone behind me, isn't there?
有人在我身后 是吧？
Only Starscream could fail to dispose of a helpless captive.
只有红蜘蛛才会在处决手无寸铁的囚犯时失手！
Uh... is it supposed to sound like that?
嗯 那是正常工作的声音吗？
Interloper!
闯入者！
You have overridden the Energon-containment protocols, haven't you?
你改写了能量容载的程序 对吧？
Clever, but not irreversible.
很聪明 不过我能修好！
There is more than one way to nullify a neural net.
要摧毁一个神经系统有很多方法
Not this time.
这次你别想！
Cliff?
小飞？
I knew you cared.
我就知道你关心我！
It appears Shockwave's arrogance was his undoing.
看来震荡波的自大出卖了他
Destroy them!
摧毁他们！
Autobots... whatever you did to the space bridge,
汽车人 不管你们对太空桥做了什么
undo it now!
快撤消！
They should really stop shooting at us if they want our help.
他们要是真想向我们寻求帮助 就应该停火
Seeing as how our exit is blocked
眼下我们的退路已经被阻断了
and we have an open space bridge portal currently set for Prime's location...
而正好有个太空桥的传送门指向擎天柱的位置
You with me?
你跟我来吗？
The space bridge... it's going to blow!
太空桥 快爆炸了！
Give it everything you got!
有什么能耐都使出来吧！
Bull's-Eye!
正中红心！
Think Shockwave survived?
你觉得震荡波还活着吗？
Hope so. I want a rematch.
最好还活着 我要再和他较量一番！
Let's find Optimus... partner.
我们去找擎天柱吧 搭档
Rich with Energon, huh?
充满能量 嗯？
Hope the whole rock doesn't look like this.
但愿整块石头不全是这番光景
Reminds me of the time I was lost in the Sea of Rust
这让我想起当年我在锈海迷失的时候
back on Cybertron,
在塞博特恩
except I was separated from my unit with absolutely no one to talk to.
不过那次我脱离了部队 连一个说话的人都没有！
Talk at?
是喋喋不休吧？
Admit it... you love the company!
承认吧 你喜欢有人陪着！
Funny...
有趣
At first, I didn't think I'd ever get used to Cliff's constant chatter.
一开始我觉得我不可能习惯飞过山的喋喋不休
Now... there's nothing louder to me than the silence.
可现在 却总是感觉过于安静了